[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trioscope automation
tutoria this is our lesson 34 as an
overall trient Tas automation Concepts
and this is our lesson 19 as an advanced
level concept
so in this lesson we'll
learn how can we use interval
syntax while using verify action mode by
using trient Taska so I would recommend
you guys to visit my previous videos
where I spoke about the verify action
mode so basically how can you automate
your test cases by using verify action
mode so in this lesson we are going to
concentrate on interval
syntax while using verify action
mode so first let us understand what is
this interval syntax so you can specify
an interval instead of a single value
when you use action mode so in our
previous lesson we have used action mode
to verify some content or we used
basically single value But
Here by using intervals in instead of
specifying single value you can
basically specify the interval so if you
specify an interval trien Tas of
verifies if a value is within the
specific range it is not verifying a
specific value but it is verifying if
the value is within the specific range
specified
range and before you specify an interval
we need to note the following you can
only specify an interval for data types
numeric and string only these okay and
then to validate a property with
intervals you can only use the
operators equal operators or not equal
operators so these two things you need
to keep in mind and there are two types
of intervals one is simple interval so
to specify an interval with equal upper
and lower boundaries will be using
single interval just keep in mind equal
equal upper and lower boundaries so if
you see the
syntax open curly braces
interval you're going to specify the
base first within the square brackets
and then you're going to specify the
limit so that means when it is
verification is
successful the verification will be
successful if the value within the range
what is the range your base minus limit
and your base plus limit for example let
us assume your base is 100 that means
what is the range your range will be 100
- 25 which is 75 and 100 + 25 which is
125 that means you're expecting your
value should be between 75 and 125 okay
and what is our next method the next
method is custom interval so to specify
an interval with unique upper and lower
boundaries in simple interval equal
upper and lower boundaries here unique
upper and lower boundaries if you see
the syntax open curly braces interval
you're going to specify the base within
the square brackets until here it same
but after that you're going to specify
both lower boundary as well as your
upper
boundary whereas in the previous way
previous we just specified the limit but
here we are going to specify lower
boundary and the upper boundary so what
is the range the range will be your base
minus lower
boundary and our upper boundary is base
plus upper boundary for example your
base is 100 I specified the lower
boundary as 10 then your lower boundary
will will be 90 and I can specify the
unique upper boundary upper boundary I
specified upper boundary 50 that means
100 + 50 which is 150 so your content
should be between 90
and okay so now let us jump onto the
system and see how can we use intervals
while automating your test cases so
first let us understand what do you want
automate okay so this is our sample app.
rentes okay where it is showing me a
different price options for my car so if
you see the silver has t22 gold 949 per
year and plattinum 1,800 per year you
see the claims discount right the silver
does not have any discount gold has a
discount of 2% Platinum has a discount
of 5% and ultimate has a discount of 10%
now this percentage the discount
percentage should be between 0 to 10 so
now I would like to
validate this particular row should have
all the values discounted values between
0 to 10 right the range between 0 to 10
how can I validate that so let us go to
your prent toas okay so let me first
scan scan the table that we are
displaying there okay let us scan the
table first okay so let's go to here
right click and click on scan
application so I would like to scan the
table control on the particular web
page so here this is my web application
click on scan and if you see you should
see the table
this is your entire table okay so here
this is your price table let's highlight
this you highlight this see this is your
price table I'm just going to select the
price table and let us save this so
before I save I would like to change the
name okay what I'm going to do I'm going
to change the name
to right okay let the name will be uh
price options okay let it be like that
okay let's save this okay and close
your xcan so let's go back to your prasa
now I want to move this module to the
right side so let us create one test
case now okay first let me create a
folder here okay let me create a folder
right click click on
[Music]
folder here I'm going to
specify
intervals okay intervals and let's
create one test
case
[Applause]
validate
discount percentage range okay I'm going
to validate the discount percentage
range
okay so here now whatever the module
that we scanned let us add this module
drag and drop
here so what what I'm going to do now
let expand this and this is your price
table so for the price table I would
like to go to the column first if you
see I want to verify the discount
percentage should be between the range
of 0 to 10 I need to see the column
Platinum first okay let's go here go to
column and select
Platinum so once I select the Platinum
here under cell let's copy this as it is
I would like to go for the
sell this one discount percentage and
this
should first let me store this into a
buffer let me store into a
buffer uh
discount claim this is the buffer i'
like to store let's store this into a
buffer okay buffer and once I store into
the buffer let's run this I want to see
if this particular value will be stor
into buffer or not okay right click and
run
it I'm just making
sure it can read the value from the
row
okay so now it's read the value let's go
to your present isasa and see the result
now so if you see here under Platinum it
stored the buffer see the value five has
been stored under discount claim buffer
value now now here
again again I want to see the cell now I
want to verify the range
here the value should
be first what is
you let us first go and see the formula
so as I told you earlier we'll see here
okay
so what is the formula to specify the
range let us first see simple interval
of simple interval it talks about your
interval base and the limit correct so
now I'm going to specify this as
braces interval see interval what is the
base I'm going to specify it as 10 in
the braces now I'm going to specify the
limit so that means what I'm saying this
cell should
have so let's close the curly bases see
now as soon as I remove this now it
should turn into a format see interval
10 your base is 10 your limit is five
which means
10 - 5
5 10 + 5 15 that means the value should
be between 5 and
15 so if you see here the value is
between five and 15 that's correct the
value is actually five that means which
comes under 5 and 15 let me run this now
right click and
run so the value should be between
pi and
10 yes so let's go to your test results
now okay let us go to your test
results so if you see here your
verification is
successful and it
says value stored here and this is
correct okay so now this is your simp
interval what about custom interval I
would like to verify the custom interval
so I'm going to specify again here I
want to verify if your claim
discount
interval and my Bas is 10 and what is
your lower limit and what is your uper
upper limit my lower limit is six and my
upper is five what do you mean by that
the meaning is the value the sell
discount claim discount cell should have
the value between 10 - 6 which is 4 and
10 + 5 15 that means the value should be
between 4 and 15 so let me run this now
if I run
this both the test steps should
pass because the value is between 5 and
15 and the value is between 4 and
15 perfect so now let us go and see our
test
results see both the
verifications both verify steps
pass so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries
hope you all understand the concept of
interval
syntax while using action mode
verify please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank
you